4qsurvey.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy | iperceptions

Last Updated: October 1, 2019.

**PREAMBLE**

iperceptions Inc. is committed to protecting the privacy of all the individuals using its website and services. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose and transfer the information that you provide to us or that we collect about you when you access and use our website at iperceptions.com (the " **Website** ") or when you access and use one of our Services through the intermediary of one of our Customers.

By using, visiting or otherwise accessing iperceptions’ Website or Services in any way (including by responding to surveys, viewing, downloading or uploading any content or material made available via the website or the services or by browsing), you expressly consent to the collection, use, disclosure and processing of information, including your data (which may include personal information) in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you are located outside of Canada, your data may be transferred through iperceptions’ Customers to iperceptions’ servers located in Canada for processing purposes. By using our website or submitting any data through iperceptions’ services or otherwise, you consent to this transfer and to the processing of your data in Canada. YOU MAY OPT OUT AT ANY TIME IN THE MANNER DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR CHOOSE NOT TO PROVIDE AN ANSWER TO ANY GIVEN SURVEY QUESTION, IF ANY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS POLICY, DO NOT ACCES OUR WEBSITE OR USE ANY OF OUR SERVICES.

**1.  DEFINITIONS**

These definitions should help you understand this policy.

When we say “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, “ **our** ” or “ **iperceptions** ”, we are referring to iperceptions Inc. a Canadian company, located at 606 Cathcart, Suite 1007, Montréal, Québec, H3B 1K9, Canada and any of our corporate affiliates. We are the owner of the Website.

When we say “ **Customer** ”, we are referring to a person or company that has subscribed to one of our Services.

When we say “ **Respondent** ”, we are referring to respondents or other participants who interact with our Services as a result of such respondents’ or participants’ relationship with one of our Customer, i.e. by responding to a survey, giving feedback through a comment card or using any other Services powered by iperceptions.

When we say “ **Visitor** ”, we are referring to a visitor of our website.

When we say “ **you** ” or “ **your** ” we are referring either to a Customer, a Respondent, a Visitor depending of the context.

When we say “ **Services** ” we are referring to survey, comment cards and other Services powered by iperceptions.

When we say “ **Privacy Policy** ” we are referring to this privacy policy which may be changed in accordance with its terms, as updated from time to time.

When we say “ **Personal information”** we are referring to any information that identified or can be used to identify an identifiable individual. Personal information includes such things as your name, address, occupation, gender, as well as others demographic information.

This Privacy Policy applies to data that may be collected through the use of iperceptions’ own Website or through iperceptions’ platform and other Services that you will visit through the websites of one or our Customers. We invite you to read the privacy policy of our Customers to understand how they process your data and Personal information.

**2\. HOW WE COLLECT AND USE YOUR INFORMATION  **

We collect information about you when you provide it directly to us, when you use one of our Services or when another person provides us with your information. We also gather certain information automatically as explained in Section 2.3 below.

We collect data directly from Visitors and from our Customer. We also collect data about Respondents on behalf of our Customers, through a Services, i.e. through a survey that you complete on our platform.

**2.1 Data collected from Visitors or Customers**

**Data collected from Visitors**

You may be asked to provide Personal information in exchange for access to white papers or other downloadable content on our Website. The data collected may include name, email addresses, mailing address, phone number, title and company, IP address and location. 

We may use this information for sales and marketing purposes, to respond to your inquiry, and to follow up with you about the products and services in which you have expressed an interest or correspond with you if necessary.

If you have subscribed to our emails or to our blog, we will also send information to you regarding content, tips, products and services that may be of interest to you. You may unsubscribe from these communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in the email or by sending us an email at [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com).

**Data collected from our Customers**

If you are one of our Customers, you can create an account on the Website to access to the Services you subscribed to. During the registration process you will be asked to submit Personal information about yourself (such as your name and email address). This information, as well with any other Personal information collected during our contractual relationship, will be used to provide you with our Services and technology solutions in accordance with the agreement executed between your company and us. This includes giving you access to our Services, providing customers’ support, communicating with you about your use of the services. We can also use this information to analyses the characteristic of our customer and to help us to improve our products and services.

**2.2 Respondent’s Data collected on behalf of Customers**

As part of our Services we may collect, process, store and share data collected from Respondents on behalf of our Customers, (the “ **Customer Data** ”) thought a Services, i.e. through a survey that you completed on our platform. In such a case, our Customer, as the owner of your data, is the data controller and we are acting under its strict instructions as the data processor. In the case where we are processing information on behalf of our Customer, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of our Customer, to better understand how it processes your data.

All data collected from Respondents is owned, controlled and managed by the Customer. We have signed agreements with all our Customer, and we process, collect, use, store and share the Customer Data only under the instruction and control of our Customer. We will only process Customer Data in the manner provided by our Customer and will not transfer any Customer Data without Customer’s prior written consent or as specifically provided under this Privacy Policy (in response to a Court Order, for example).

Our Services do not by default collect, store, handle or otherwise process Personal Information.   However, a Customer may decide to collect Personal Information through our Services (eg. a survey could include questions which ask Respondents to provide an account number or an e-mail address). In addition, Customers may request that the IP addresses of Respondents be collected as part of the Services. IP addresses may be considered Personal Information in certain jurisdictions. We may also otherwise inadvertently collect Personal Information or sensitive information (as health or ethnic information) when you voluntarily provide such information in “open-text” type questions. If you voluntarily provide us with Personal or sensitive information, you consent to the use of such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you are a Respondent located in the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”), each of our Customers processing your Personal information is required under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) to provide you with information or access to their privacy policy explaining how they will process your data. Please check their privacy policies before you submit any Personal Information on our platform. If you do not agree with the content of their privacy policies, do not reply to the survey and do not share information with us.

Your submission of Personal Information in any survey or comment card is at all time voluntary and optional. You may opt out of responding at any time. However, if you do respond, you consent to its provision to us for the purpose of delivering the services to our Customers.

As part of our Services, we compile data collected from our online surveys to produce benchmark reports for Customers as well as media and other interested parties. Data provided by Respondents on Customers’ online surveys is compiled and aggregated to create generic profiles of users of the websites being studied (containing no Personal Information). Open-ended responses are compiled and reported as is. Customers can export, share, or publish data from their surveys. We provide various features to export, share, or publish your survey questions, responses, and results in summary or detailed format. Please refer to the Customer’s own privacy policy for more details on use and disclosure of your data. We may also use Customer Data (non Personal Information), including online survey questions and Respondents’ responses, as well as aggregated and anonymized data we collect through survey results and transactional and performance data related to use of the Services to help analysis and to help us provide and improve our services.

iperceptions treats all Customer Data as confidential and safeguards such Customer Data according to industry best practices and all applicable laws.

**2.3 Automatically collected data**

Except as provided in this Section 2.3, we do not collect, retain or share end user information including IP addresses, unique user identifiers, or personally identifiable information automatically gathered on websites or apps not owned by iperceptions. We however may gather certain information automatically on our own website or on the websites of our Customers ​as part of the services we provide and store it in the web server log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses of Respondents, Customers and Visitors, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), mobile carrier, mobile device, operating system, referring/exit pages, the URLs of sites from which a Visitors arrives or leaves a website, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to monitor the effectiveness of marketing efforts, including which websites refer the most people to iperceptions or its Customers’ websites, to understand Visitors’ movements around iperceptions’ or its Customer’s website, and to improve the quality of the Services and Website performance, to aid solving technical problems, and to gather demographic information about iperceptions’ or its Customers’ Visitors base as a whole (the IP addresses are analyzed in the aggregate). We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you, except where you have chosen to provide it. We retain data collected in a database used only for internal purposes and do not sell data collected to third parties. ​For clarity, we do not collect any information from websites we do not own without specific written consent of the website owner or operator, who are responsible of obtaining said consent from their visitors.

We may also generate, use and disclose aggregated and/or anonymized information and statistics about the Website for marketing and strategic purposes. However, no individual will be individually identifiable from these aggregated and/or anonymized information and statistics.

**2.4. Information from Third Parties**

We may collect your personal information from third parties when you authorize those third parties to share your information with us. We can also receive information about you and your activities on and off the Services from third-party partner, such as advertising and market research partner who provide us with information about your interest in and engagement with our Services and online advertisements. We can also receive your contact information from a Customer who will allow you to access our Services as one of the Customer’s manager of our Services.

**2.5 Cookies and others tracking technologies**

We use Cookies and other technologies to help personalize and improve our Visitor’s online experience and the overall quality of the Services. “Cookies” are software methods and protocols used for storing data in a web browser. For the purpose of this document, Cookies refers to both HTTP Cookies as defined by the IETF and the local and session storage methods of the Web Storage specification as defined by the World Wide Web consortium. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer or device. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. iperceptions may use a third-party tracking service that uses images, scripts, page tags (also known as web beacons) and other tracking technologies to track non-personal information about visitors to our Website in the aggregate. This data includes Visitors statistics. We will not request, access or otherwise track any location-based information from your mobile device. In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing the Services to Visitors, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser for the enhancement of your Visitor experience by providing more relevant advertising. If you want more information about cookies and how to control or disable cookies, you can visit our [cookies policy](https://www.iperceptions.com/en/legal/cookies?hsLang=en&__hstc=162943075.ac302e2855aacfaf02f4f43549c87169.1582077415879.1582077415879.1582077415879.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582077415880&__hsfp=3924935683). If you reject cookies, you may still use our services, but your ability to use some features or areas of our services may be limited.

**2.6 Blogs, forums, testimonials, social media widgets**

Our Website may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums, you should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your information from our blog or community forum, [contact us](https://www.iperceptions.com/en/contact-us?hsLang=en&__hstc=162943075.ac302e2855aacfaf02f4f43549c87169.1582077415879.1582077415879.1582077415879.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582077415880&__hsfp=3924935683).

We may contact you to request your permission to post testimonials on our website that you may submit to us from time to time.

Our website and some surveys include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and Widgets, such as the “Share this” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third-party company providing it.

**3\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We do not sell or rent your data to third party. We only share your data as specifically provided into this privacy policy.

**3.1 Sharing with our Partners**

We may provide your data, including your Personal Information, to companies that provide Services to help us with our business activities (our “Partners”). These services may include, for example website analytics, hosting services or email services. We have written agreement with all of our Partners authorizing them to use your data only as necessary to provide these services to us. Our Partners are bound by strict confidentiality and non-disclosure obligations to ensure your data is adequately safeguarded. These Partners may transfer your data outside of the country from which you are accessing this Website including but not limited to the USA, **and they may be required to disclose Personal information under the laws of their jurisdiction.**

**3.2 Data collected on behalf of Customers**

As we collect data from Respondent only on behalf of our Customer and in compliance with their instructions, we will share the information collected with the relevant Customer, in accordance with the terms of the agreement we have with them. If you want more information about the way your data, including your Personal Information if any, are processed by our Customers, please read the Customer privacy policy.

**3.3 Other websites**

The Website may contain links to other websites, such as Facebook or LinkedIn which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. **We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Website and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects Personal information.**

**3.4 Other disclosures**

In addition to any disclosure you may have consented to or permitted under the terms of this Privacy Policy, we may transfer your data, including Personal information to third parties in the following limited circumstances: 1) information you expressly consent to be shared; 2) when relating to anonymized information (individuals cannot be identified by it); 3) when you decide to make the information indexable by search engines, to share or to distribute the information to people or otherwise to make it available to the public; 4) to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request within or outside your country of residence when we have a good faith belief that the law requires it; 5) to enforce this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or a service agreement, including investigation of potential violations thereof; 6) to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or protect the operations or Visitors; 7) to protect the rights, property or safety of iperceptions, our Visitors, the public, or others; 8) in connection with an acquisition, merger, change in control, debt financing, reorganization, sale of assets, bankruptcy or other change of our’ corporate structure or status; or 9) sweepstakes administrators, as necessary in connection with the performance of requested services or solutions, or as otherwise appropriate in connection with a legitimate need.

**3.5 International transfer**

iperceptions is a Canadian based company. If you are located outside of Canada, your data will be transferred through our Website or iperceptions’ Customers to iperceptions’ servers located in Canada for processing purposes. By using our Website or submitting any data through iperceptions’ Services or otherwise, you consent to this transfer and to the processing of your data, including your Personal information, if any, in Canada.

Your information may be accessed by employees, Customers and Partners, transferred to, and/or stored in any country in the world, including outside Canada and the EEA for the purposes set out in this Privacy policy. Such countries may have lower data protection standards than Canada and countries within the EEA, and our Customers and Partners may be required to disclose personal information under the laws of their jurisdiction. However, we will ensure that data protection requirements applicable to where the information was collected are imposed on the recipient when it receives and uses such exported information.

**4\. HOW TO ACCESS AND CONTROL YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION  **

**4.1 Customer and Visitors of iperceptions website**

If you are one of our Customer or Visitors, contact us at: [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com) with your request and we will respond within a reasonable delay. iperceptions will endeavor to fulfill any requests to correct, update or delete your Personal Information unless such information is required to be retained by law, for legitimate business, technical or security purposes (such as storage in backup media created as part of our routine system backup procedures, or if jeopardizing the privacy of others) or, as provided in this Privacy Policy.

**4.2 Respondents**

If you are a Respondent, as your Data is owned by our Customers, we generally cannot respond to such requests. Consequently, communicate directly with the Customer if you want to access, update, or delete any data provided. Any change or deletion to your data will be limited to data related to the given Customer and not to any data that may have been provided through iperceptions’ services on other Customer websites.

**4.3 If you are an EEA resident**

You have specific rights regarding the handling of your information under the EU General Data Protection Regulation. The data controller of your personal information must reply to your request relating to: your right to be informed; your right of access; your right to rectification; your right to erasure; your right to restrict processing; your right to data portability; your right to object and your rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling. Some of your rights may be subject to some limitations or exceptions.

**EEA Customer or EEA Visitors**

If you are a Customer or a Visitors of our Website, we are the data controller of your information. Please contact us at [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com), with your name, email address, your quality: Customer or Visitor and any additional information we would need to reply to your request and we will reply to your request in a 30 days delay.

**EEA Respondent**

If you are a Respondent and have completed a survey or a comment card, the data controller of your information is our Customer, the owner of the website on which you took to the survey or completed the comment card.

Therefore, please directly contact the Customer through which you submitted your personal information. As our Customers are the Data Controller of your Personal Information, they are responsible of handling and replying to your request. They will then inform us if needed to comply with your request. If you decide anyway to contact us, note that we will send your request to our Customer in order for it to reply to your request. For that we will need you to provide us with the following information in order to identify you and our Customer: the website on which you took the survey or completed the comment card, your name or the email that you would have inputted, your IP address and any other information that will help us to identify you and find your Personal information.

**4.4 If you are a California resident**

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of Personal information we share with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates' direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of Personal information shared with third parties and used for direct marketing purposes and the name and address of the third parties that received such Personal information. If you are a California resident and want a copy of this notice, please submit a written request at [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com) or to the following address: iperceptions Inc. , 606 Rue Cathcart, #1007, Montreal, QC, Canada, H3B 1K9, Fax: 514-484-2600, Attention: General Manager. In your request, please specify that you want a "California Privacy Rights Notice." Once we have received your request, we will respond within 30 days.

**5\. HOW WE STORE AND SECURE YOUR INFORMATION  **

We take all reasonable precautions to protect against loss and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of Personal information using secure server hosting locations with 24×7 security and monitoring, firewall protection, controlled access and encryption technology to protect your data. These measures include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security practices. However, considering transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure, we do not warrant that it can ensure absolute security despite the security safeguards in place.

Any supplied sensitive/credit information provided is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our PCI Compliant Payment gateway providers’ database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems and are required to keep the information confidential. After a transaction, information such as credit card numbers are not stored on our servers.

We restrict access to Personal information to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Website and the Services.

You’ll find more detail on our security measure and on our certifications on [this page](https://www.iperceptions.com/en/legal/information-security?hsLang=en&__hstc=162943075.ac302e2855aacfaf02f4f43549c87169.1582077415879.1582077415879.1582077415879.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582077415880&__hsfp=3924935683).

iperceptions complies with the Canadian Federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). For Respondents and Visitors from Member States of the European Economic Area, iperceptions also complies with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).

**6\. HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION  **

We will retain Personal information of our Visitors and Customers for as long as it is needed : 1) to provide products and Services that you or your organization have requested; 2) to communicate with you about a request you have made to us; 3) to manage your choices and rights you have exercised pursuant to this Privacy Notice; 4) to enable you maintain an account with us, provided that you or the organization through which your account was created have not otherwise requested that we delete your information; 5) to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, to demonstrate compliance, 6) to resolve dispute and to enforce our rights and agreements.

We will retain Respondents’ information we process on behalf of our Customers as instructed by our Customer or for as long as needed to provide Services to our Customers or as necessary to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, to demonstrate compliance, to resolve dispute and to enforce our rights and agreements. By default, and if not instructed otherwise by our Customers, we will erase information collected through a survey on behalf of one our Customer three years following the end of such specific survey. If you are a Respondent and want to know how long your information will be stored by us, you have to read the privacy policy of the Customer or you will have to ask directly the Customer.

If you would like to know how long we retain cookies, please refers to our [cookies policy](https://www.iperceptions.com/en/legal/cookies?hsLang=en&__hstc=162943075.ac302e2855aacfaf02f4f43549c87169.1582077415879.1582077415879.1582077415879.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582077415880&__hsfp=3924935683).

**7\. CHILDREN**

Our Website and Services are not designed or intended for use by children under 16 and we do not intentionally or knowingly collect data from children under 16 or allow them to register, although the sites we survey may offer children’s services for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you should not participate in surveys or use any Website unless a parent or guardian is present. Children under 16 may not submit any information to us, and if we discover that we have inadvertently gathered any such information for a child under 16 or such child has created an account, we will take steps to delete any such information and close that account as soon as possible. Children over 16 should only provide us with information if they have explicit permission from a parent or legal guardian. If your child has submitted information, and you wish to review, change and/or delete such information as well as refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child’s information, or if you have reason to believe that this has occurred involving a child under 16, please contact us: [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com).

**8\. CHANGES**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes will be posted on our Website and any other places we deem appropriate so that you can be aware of how we process the data we collect. Changes become effective immediately upon posting. If you object to any changes, you may cancel, deactivate your account, if any, or not respond to a survey.

**9\. HOW TO SUBMIT PRIVACY RELATED INQUIRIES AND COMPLAINTS**

If you have questions related to this Privacy Policy, please email us at: [privacy@iperceptions.com](mailto:privacy@iperceptions.com), or write us at:

iperceptions Inc. Attention: General Manager.

606 Rue Cathcart, #1007                   

Montreal, QC

Canada  
H3B 1K9

Fax: 514-484-2600

When contacting us, please be sure to provide us with your exact e-mail address, name, address, and/or telephone number(s) so that we may handle your request appropriately.

If you are a resident of the EEA and have an unresolved privacy or Personal information collection, use, or disclosure concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact the EU Data Protection Authorities. For more information on how to contact the EU Data Protection Authorities, _[click here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm)_.
